savagearms.com 2016-06-03

# Privacy Policy - Vista Outdoor

This Privacy Policy applies to Vista Outdoor Inc. and Vista Outdoor Sales LLC, as well as our subsidiaries and affiliates and our trusted family of brands (collectively, “Vista Outdoor”).  Vista Outdoor has created this Policy to let you know we take your privacy seriously. This Policy explains our information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected from our websites, online applications, kiosks, mobile applications, email, telephone inquiries, promotions, warranty registrations, newsletter service, surveys, forums, sweepstakes/contest entries, Idea Exchange, ratings and review service, social media sites and the websites hosted by our service providers and merchant associates (collectively, the “Services”).

  1. **Types of Information Collected.**

When using our Services, we may collect (ourselves or through our trusted service providers or business associates) your name, age, gender, company name, postal address, e-mail address, phone number, zip code and credit card information (“Personal Information”).  We may also collect other information that you submit or disclose in connection with the Services, such as product interests, reviews, feedback, testimonials, ideas, postings, submissions, photographs, diagrams, drawings, plans, notes, suggestions, inventions, creative materials, videos, designs, and other information (“User-Generated Content”).

Vista Outdoor may, directly or through a third party, collect information about you and your use of our Services whenever you use the Services.  For instance, we may collect various forms of information such as entry and exit points for our Services ( _i.e_., referring URLs or domains), Services traffic statistics, operating system and browser type (collectively “Traffic Data”). Traffic Data is anonymous information that does not personally identify you but is helpful for marketing purposes or for improving your experience on the Services. In addition, when you request pages on our Services, our servers automatically log your IP address. An IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer whenever you are surfing the web. Vista Outdoor may store some information on your computer in the form of a “cookie” or similar file to help us maintain and improve these Services in many ways. A “cookie” is a small amount of data that is transferred to your browser by a web server and can only be read by the server that gave it to you. It functions as your identification card, recording such things as Internet addresses, passwords, and preferences. It cannot be executed as code or deliver viruses. With most Internet browsers, you can erase “cookies” from your computer hard drive, block all “cookies,” or receive a warning before a “cookie” is stored. The “Help” portion of the toolbar on most browsers will tell you how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie, or how to disable cookies altogether. Please refer to your browser instructions to learn more about these functions. Enabling cookies allows you to take full advantage of all the features on the Services and we recommend that you leave them turned on. If you elect to block the cookies, we will not be able to provide you with a personalized experience on our Services. We may also include social media features, such as the Facebook Like button, Google Plus, Pinterest, and Twitter widgets. These features may collect information about your IP address and which page you’re visiting on our site(s), and they may set a cookie to make sure the feature functions properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our site. Your interactions with those features are governed by this Privacy Policy and the privacy policies of the companies that provide them.

In some instances, Vista Outdoor may use tracking scripts or “tracers” that recognize a unique identifier from a cookie placed on your hard drive by another website. These are used by Vista Outdoor solely to gauge the success of our own advertising. For instance, we may use a tracer to determine whether you visit certain web pages where Vista Outdoor may have placed a banner ad. We do not use tracers to gather information on your use of the Internet unrelated to Vista Outdoor. Please note that Vista Outdoor does not use tracers to identify your personal information, and you remain anonymous unless and until you communicate with Vista Outdoor.

The Services are not intended for children under the age of 13. We will not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from the Services from visitors in this age group. We encourage parents to talk to their children about their use of the Internet and the information they disclose to Web sites. Parents can also select “Personal Information / Opt Out” at our [Contact Us](http://vistaoutdoor.com/contact-us/ "Contact Us") page to access, change, or delete the personal information that has been submitted by a child.

  2. **Use of Information Collected**.

Vista Outdoor may use Personal Information to send you information about us and our products, including news and promotional material, to solicit information from you, to provide a response or confirmation to an order placed on our merchant site(s) and for marketing research. We may use your Personal Information to customize the Services and display content that we think you might be interested in according to your preferences.  We may use non-identifying and aggregate information to better design our website.

  3. **Sharing of Personal Information.**

Vista Outdoor will not sell, rent, edit or intentionally disclose any Personal Information, including its contents or your use of the Site, without your prior consent, but Vista Outdoor may securely share your Personal Information, without your prior consent, for the limited purposes noted below:

  1. Third Parties. Vista Outdoor may share Personal Information with its service providers and trusted business associates to perform functions such as collecting and analyzing user information, conducting contests, sweepstakes, and other promotions, fulfilling rebate submissions, credit card processing as it relates to placing orders, delivering packages, sending postal mail and e-mail, removing repetitive information from customer lists, analyzing data, providing marketing assistance, providing search results and links (including paid listings and links) and providing customer service. These third parties will only use your Personal Information for those purposes required to perform their functions.
  2. Business Transfers. As Vista Outdoor continues to develop its business, we might sell or buy subsidiaries or business units. In such transactions, customer information generally is one of the transferred business assets but remains subject to the obligations made in any pre-existing privacy policy.
  3. Legal Obligations. Vista Outdoor may share your Personal Information if we have a good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (i) comply with legal process or other legal requirements of any governmental authority; (ii) protect and defend the rights or property of Vista Outdoor; (iii) enforce this Agreement; (iv) protect the interests of other users of the Site or any other person; or (v) operate or conduct maintenance and repair of the Site or equipment.
  4. **Protection of Personal Information.**

We want you to have continuing trust in Vista Outdoor and in our products and services. In order to prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, we have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet or any wireless network can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, you acknowledge that: (a) there are security and privacy limitations of the Internet which are beyond our control; (b) the security, integrity and privacy of any and all information and data exchanged between you and us through our Services cannot be guaranteed; and (c) any such information and data may be viewed or tampered with in transit by a third party.

  5. **Submission of Confidential Information.**

Other than Personal Information, Vista Outdoor does not treat User-Generated Content as confidential.  You should not use the Services as a means of submitting information you consider to be confidential or proprietary.  Any submission of User Generated Content will be considered a contribution to Vista Outdoor for further use in its sole discretion, regardless of any proprietary claims or reservation of rights noted, and shall become the sole property of Vista Outdoor. Vista Outdoor shall own exclusive rights, including all intellectual property rights, and shall be entitled to the unrestricted use of User-Generated Content for any purpose, commercial or otherwise, without acknowledgment or compensation to you.  You irrevocably waive any and all “moral rights” in User-Generated Content, including the rights of paternity and integrity.

  6. **Other Limits to Your Privacy.**

The Services may contain links to non-Vista Outdoor websites.  We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of non-Vista Outdoor websites.  We have no control over the use of such websites and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose any Personal Information or User-Generated Content on these websites.

  7. **User Choice Regarding Collection, Use and Distribution of Personal Information.**

You may choose not to provide Vista Outdoor with any Personal Information or User-Generated Content.  However, your access to some of the Services may be limited.  If you wish to update your Personal Information, have questions about your Personal Information or do not wish to receive information and promotional material from us you may select the appropriate “opt-out” option or let us know by selecting “Personal Information / Opt Out” at our [Contact Us](http://vistaoutdoor.com/contact-us/ "Contact Us") page.

  8. **Updates and Changes to Privacy Policy.**

We reserve the right, at any time and without notice, to add to, change, update or modify this Privacy Policy, simply by posting such change, update or modification on the Site. Any such change, update or modification will be effective immediately upon posting on the Site. Updates and changes to the Website Terms and Conditions of Use Agreement and the Privacy Policy will continue to govern your use of the Site even if you elect not to receive notice of such changes.

  9. **How to Contact Us.**

Should you have other questions or concerns about our Privacy Policy, including requests by California residents for information about disclosure of Personal Information to a third party for direct marketing purposes, please let us know by selecting “Personal Information / Opt Out” at our [Contact Us](http://vistaoutdoor.com/contact-us/ "Contact Us") page or write to: Digital Marketing and E-Commerce Director, Marketing Department, Vista Outdoor, 900 Bob Ehlen Drive, Anoka, MN 55303. If you are a copyright owner or an agent thereof and believe that any User-Generated Content infringes upon your copyrights, you may submit a notification pursuant to the Digital Millennium Copyright Act (“DMCA”) by providing Vista Outdoor with the following information in writing (see 17 U.S.C 512(c)(3) for further detail): (i) a physical or electronic signature of a person authorized to act on behalf of the owner of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed; (ii) identification of the copyrighted work claimed to have been infringed, or, if multiple copyrighted works at a single online site are covered by a single notification, a representative list of such works at that site; (iii) identification of the material that is claimed to be infringing or to be the subject of infringing activity and that is to be removed or access to which is to be disabled and information reasonably sufficient to permit Vista Outdoor to locate the material; (iv) information reasonably sufficient to permit Vista Outdoor to contact you, such as an address, telephone number, and, if available, an electronic mail; (v) a statement that you have a good faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; and (vi) a statement that the information in the notification is accurate, and under penalty of perjury, that you are authorized to act on behalf of the owner of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed. You may contact Vista Outdoor’s designated Copyright Agent by selecting “Copyright Inquiry” at our [Contact Us](http://vistaoutdoor.com/contact-us/ "Contact Us") page, by writing to DMCA Agent, Legal Department, Vista Outdoor, 900 Bob Ehlen Drive, Anoka, MN 55303, or by calling 763-323-2300.
